Guide to the Harry August Schoth Papers 1910-1970
Oregon State University Archives
Harry August Schoth Papers
1910-1970
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center 121 The Valley Library Oregon State University Corvallis, OR 97331-4501 Phone: 541-737-2165 Email: archives@oregonstate.edu Web: http://osulibrary.oregonstate.edu/archives
Consult repository.
Schoth, H. A. (Harry August), b. 1891.
7.1 cubic feet
The Schoth Papers document research in cover crops (vetches and clovers), forage crops, and turf and other grasses conducted by Schoth as an agronomist with the U.S. Department of Agriculture at Oregon State College.
Biographical Note:
Schoth was born in Hannah, Wyoming on May 24, 1891. He came to Oregon Agricultural College as a student in 1909, and received the B.S. in 1914 and the M.S. in 1917. Schoth worked as a Fellow at OAC from 1914-1916 and became an instructor (courtesy) in Farm Crops in 1924. He went to work for the U.S. Department of Agriculture in 1917 as a Scientific Assistant. During his USDA career he was an Assistant Agronomist in Forage Crop Investigations, Associate Agronomist and Senior Agronomist. Schoth retired from the USDA in 1961.
In 1926 he worked with Shifting Sand Dune Control for the U.S. Navy. In 1962 Schoth received the Gold Medal Award for Distinguished Service to Agriculture from the Oregon Farm Bureau for developing nearly 50 commercially-improved varieties of legumes and grasses, which contributed to the state's burgeoning seed industry. He also received an award from the American Grasslands Council and the USDA's Superior Service Award. Schoth died on July 31, 1975.
The collection includes correspondence with other agronomists and seed companies, subject information files and research reports pertaining to Schoth's research interests and field notebooks documenting field trials at the college's various research farms around Corvallis. Most of the photographs depict grasses and cover crops.
Papers are organized into 8 series: I. Correspondence; II. Research & Information; III. Dated Material; IV. Publications; V. Bulletin of the Green Section of the U.S. Golf Association; VI. Field Notebooks; VII. Maps, Plans and Charts; and VIII. Photographs. Series 1 and 2 are arranged alphabetically by correspondent and by subject; series 3 and 5 are arranged chronologically; and series 6 is loosely arranged by subject.
Crop Science Department Records (RG 95); Agricultural Communications Photographic Collection (P 120).
United States Golf Association. Green Section. Bulletin of the Green Section of the U.S. Golf Association.
Cover crops.; Crops--Research--Oregon.; Agriculture--Research--Oregon.; Grasses--Oregon.; Turfgrasses--Oregon.; Turf management--Periodicals.; Golf courses--Periodicals.
Photographs.; Maps.
Oregon; Photographs; Agriculture; Maps
- Correspondence, 1916-1937; Series I
  - H.L. Alexander, 1934 (Box 1)
  - E.R. Bogusch, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Victor R. Boswell, 1930-1932 (Box 1)
  - Cyrus Briggs, 1923-1930 (Box 1)
  - Clark Q. Brown, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Burlingham, 1931-1932 (Box 1)
  - Lyman Carrier, 1925-1927 (Box 1)
  - E.S. Center, 1926-1929 (Box 1)
  - P.V. Cardon, 1937 (Box 1)
  - B.W. Cooney, 1922-1929 (Box 1)
  - John W. Cunningham, 1927 (Box 1)
  - S.B. Detwiler, 1934 (Box 1)
  - A.E. Engbretson, 1922-1931 (Box 1)
  - C.R. Enlow, 1935 (Box 1)
  - Foreign, 1922-1929 (Box 1)
  - Morris Halperin, 1931-1935 (Box 1)
  - Virgil B. Hawk, 1935 (Box 1)
  - H.B. Howell, 1922-1929 (Box 1)
  - G.R. Hyslop, 1920-1929 (Box 1)
  - Immediate Attention, 1934 (Box 1)
  - John J. Inskeep, 1927-1931 (Box 1)
  - J.T. Jardine, 1922-1929 (Box 1)
  - Dean E.C. Johnson, 1932 (Box 1)
  - W. Wray Lawrence & Victor Johnson, 1926-1930 (Box 1)
  - R.G. Larson, 1923-1931 (Box 1)
  - Wm. E. Lawerence, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Lilly Seed Company, 1928-1931 (Box 1)
  - Elbert M. Long, 1934 (Box 1)
  - McCullough Seed Company, 1929-1930 (Box 1)
  - Roland Mckee, 1916-1924 (Box 1)
  - Mckee, 1919-1931 (Box 1)
  - Mckee, 1937 (Box 1)
  - J.L. Mahoney, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - John Monteith Jr., 1930-1931 (Box 1)
  - B.Y. Morrison, 1934 (Box 1)
  - W.J. Morse/Charles W. Reed, 1921-1927 (Box 1)
  - L.S. Mullen, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - A.J. Pieters, 1934-1935, 1937 (Box 1)
  - A.J. Pieters/L.W. Kephart, 1922-1928 (Box 1)
  - A.J. Pieters/L.W. Kephart, 1920-1927 (Box 1)
  - C.V. Piper, 1916-1925 (Box 1)
  - Port of Portland, 1928-1929 (Box 1)
  - Portland Seed Company, 1927-1931 (Box 1)
  - G.W. Prescott, 1934 (Box 1)
  - Philips G. Putnam, 1934 (Box 1)
  - W.A. Rockie/A.L. Hafenrichter, 1934-1935 (Box 1)
  - Wm. G. Scarlett & Company, 1927-1929 (Box 1)
  - Schafer, Washington Experiment Station, 1935 (Box 1)
  - W.A. Schoenfield, 1937 (Box 1)
  - H.A. Schoth, 1937 (Box 1)
  - E.C. Scott, 1937 (Box 2)
  - F.P. Sipe, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - C.S. Swingle, 1934 (Box 2)
  - H.L. Westover, 1937 (Box 2)
  - H.N. Vinall, 1924-1937 (Box 2)
- Research and Information, 1910-1961; Series II
  - Airway Service, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Alfalfa, Ladak, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Alfalfa Nurseries, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Army Information, 1928-1930 (Box 2)
  - Artichokes, 1928-1930 (Box 2)
  - Austrian Pea Seed, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Authorization, Memorandums Project, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Automobile, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Beets, Suger, 1928-1929 (Box 2)
  - Bentgrass, 1927 (Box 2)
  - "Bications", 1953 (Box 2)
  - Bluegrass, Newport, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Building(new), 1933-1934 (Box 2)
  - Checklist of seeds collected, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Class Notes, 1910-1918 (Box 2)
  - Clover, Anthracnose Resistant Red, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Clover, Button, 1921-1922 (Box 2)
  - Clover, Eureka/Soybeans, 1920-1921 (Box 2)
  - Clover, Ladino, 1924 (Box 2)
  - Clover, Subterranean, 1922 & 1929 (Box 2)
  - Clover, Sweet, 1920-1921 (Box 2)
  - C.W.A., 1933-1934 (Box 2)
  - Forage Crop Notes (Box 2)
  - Forage Crop Investigation, 1922-1923 (Box 2)
  - Forage Projects, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Gardens, Grass, 1919-1921 (Box 2)
  - Gardens, Turf, 1928-1929 (Box 2)
  - Golf Grass, 1923-1929 (Box 2)
  - Grass, Reed Canary, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Grasses - Seed, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Grass, Sudan and Millets, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Highways, 1930-1933 (Box 2)
  - Insects, 1918-1920 (Box 2)
  - Machinery, Threshing, 1922-1924 (Box 2)
  - Consolidated Mining & Smelting Company, 1930-1931 (Box 2)
  - Oats, "Support", 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Osterdamia Japonica, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Pacific, Southern, 1928-1931 (Box 2)
  - Piper Lab, Seattle, 1920-1926 (Box 2)
  - Plant Introductions (Box 2)
  - Plant Introduction - Ryerson, 1930-1934 (Box 2)
  - Plants of the Pacific Coast, 1921-1922 (Box 2)
  - Poa Bulbosa (grass), 1928-1930 (Box 2)
  - Positions and Applications, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Radio Talks, 1926-1929 (Box 2)
  - Reports, 1927-1928 (Box 2)
  - Ribes Control, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Sand Dune Control, 1930 (Box 2)
  - Sand Dunes, 1935 (Box 2)
  - Sand Dune Control, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Seed Council, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Seed Houses, 1920-1931 (Box 2)
  - Silage, 1921-1923 (Box 2)
  - Soil Conservation Service, 1934 (Box 2)
  - Soils and Fertilizers, 1937 (Box 2)
  - Spartina, 1929 (Box 2)
  - Station Building, 1930-1932 (Box 2)
  - Station Statistics, 1916-1917 (Box 2)
  - Other Stations, 1918-1923 (Box 2)
  - Sunflowers, 1923 (Box 2)
  - Tangier Peat, 1920-1923 (Box 2)
  - Tillamook, 1934-1935 (Box 2)
  - Trefoil, Yellow, 1932 (Box 2)
  - Vetch, Crown, 1931 (Box 2)
  - Vetch, Hungarian, 1922-1924 (Box 2)
  - Vetch, Purple, 1919-1923 (Box 2)
  - Vetch, Wolly Podded, 1924 (Box 2)
  - Vetch, Miscellaneous, 1918-1921 (Box 2)
  - Weeds, 1937 (Box 2)
- Dated Material, 1912-1969; Series III
  - 1912-1919 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Grain Hay Report (Box 3)
    - Experimental Crop Report (Box 3)
  - 1920-1925 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Memorandums (Box 3)
    - Silage Report (Box 3)
    - Forage and Root Crop Notes (Box 3)
    - Summary of Farm Crops Committee Meeting (Box 3)
  - 1926 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Data on 1926 Plot Seedings of Red Clover (Box 3)
  - 1927 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Bulletins (Box 3)
    - Winter Cover Crops (Box 3)
    - Pasture Experiments (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, January-July, 1928 (Box 3)
  - August-December, 1928 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Lolium Data (Box 3)
    - Agricultural Bulletin (Box 3)
  - January-August, 1929: (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Notes (Box 3)
    - Subterranean Clover Bulletin (Box 3)
    - "The Pacific Homestead" (Box 3)
  - September-December, 1929 (Box 3)
    - USDA Application for Membership (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Articles (Box 3)
  - January-February, 1930 (Box 3)
    - Alfalfa Conference (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 1930 (Box 3)
  - January-April, 1931 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - May-June, 1931 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Seed Production Subject to Shipment in Oregon (Box 3)
  - July-September, 1931 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Forage Crop Gazette (Box 3)
  - October-November, 1931 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - December, 1931 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Developement of Forage & Seed Improvement and Production (Box 3)
    - Notes (Box 3)
    - Project (Box 3)
  - 1932 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Notes (Box 3)
    - Improvement of Oregon Pastures for Dairy Cattle (Box 3)
    - Breeding Work-Vinall and Enlow (Box 3)
    - Austrian Winter Peas For the Northwest (Box 3)
  - March-May, 1933 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous, 1933 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence and Telegrams (Box 3)
    - Forage and Seed Crops in Western Washington (Box 3)
    - Journal of Chemical Education (Box 3)
  - January-April, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Articles (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - May-July, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Articles (Box 3)
    - Diseases of the Austrian Winter Pea (Box 3)
  - August, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Transportation Requests Reported As Lost (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - September, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - October, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Best Grass for Wet Land (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - November, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
    - Newspaper Articles (Box 3)
  - December, 1934 (Box 3)
    - Report on International Crop Improvement Association (Box 3)
    - Newspaper Article (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - January, 1935 (Box 3)
    - Bureau of Plant Industry (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - February-April, 1935 (Box 3)
    - Correspondence (Box 3)
  - May, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - June, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Extracts from Report of Secretary's Committee (Box 4)
    - Memorandum for Mr. H.H. Bennett (Box 4)
    - Progress Report-Superphosphates (Box 4)
    - Progress-Basic slag (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - June 6-December 18, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - General Memorandum of Understanding between BPI & SCS (Box 4)
    - Field Memorandum (Box 4)
  - July, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - August, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Memorandum for Field Men (Box 4)
  - September, 1935 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - January-June, 1936 (Box 4)
    - Perilla-Bureau of Plant Industry (Box 4)
    - Memorandums (Box 4)
    - Potash and Clover for Better Pasture (Box 4)
    - Receipts (Box 4)
    - Report on Feasability of Grazing Livestock (Box 4)
  - March-April, 1936 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - July, 1936 (Box 4)
    - Weekly Itinerary Report (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Photos (Box 4)
  - August, 1936 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Receipts (Box 4)
  - September, 1936 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - October, 1936 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Semi-Monthly Newsletter (Box 4)
    - Experiments (Box 4)
  - November, 1936 (Box 4)
    - Memoranda (Box 4)
    - The Value of Foreign Red Clover in the U.S. (Box 4)
    - Bureau of Plant Industry-Purchases, Orders, Supplies (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - 1937 (Box 4)
    - Outline of a Suggested Research Program (Box 4)
    - Fourth International Grassland Congress (Box 4)
    - Digest of Pasture Research Literature (Box 4)
    - Forage Crop Gazette (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - 1940-43 (Box 4)
    - Climate of the States-Oregon (Box 4)
    - Production and Income Statistics (Box 4)
    - Research Report No. 2 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - 1941 (Box 4)
    - Daily Digest (Box 4)
  - 1945-49 (Box 4)
    - I Believe in Oregon State (Box 4)
    - Needed Program on Legume Improvement (Box 4)
    - Data for Legume Seed Insect Project (Box 4)
    - Christmas Around the World (Box 4)
    - Commercial Review (Box 4)
    - Research Project Forage & Cover Crop Seed Improvement (Box 4)
  - January-May, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
    - Vouchers (Box 4)
    - Study of Willamette Valley Hill Pastures (Box 4)
    - Research Project (Box 4)
  - June, 1946 (Box 4)
    - Correspondence (Box 4)
  - July, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - August, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Vouchers (Box 5)
    - Grasses Considered as Satisfactory for Airport Turf (Box 5)
  - September, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Vouchers (Box 5)
  - October, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Vouchers (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Summary Report, 7/1/44-7/30/46 (Box 5)
  - November, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Vouchers (Box 5)
    - Cost Estimate for Extention Sprinkler (Box 5)
  - December, 1946 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Vouchers (Box 5)
  - January-April, 1947 (Box 5)
  - May-July, 1947 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Master Outline for Development of Assigned Topics (Box 5)
    - Logged-Off Land Utilization (Box 5)
    - Vouchers (Box 5)
  - 1950-51 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Granger Lotus Seed Allotments (Box 5)
    - The Spreading Character in Rhizome Alfalfa (Box 5)
    - Agriculture Productive Capacity in Oregon (Box 5)
    - Estimates on Use of Farmland (Box 5)
  - 1952-53 (Box 5)
    - Memorandum of Understanding (Box 5)
    - The Key to Grassland Agriculture (Box 5)
    - Abstract from FC Memorandum No. 1 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - 1954-55 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - New York Herald Tribune (Box 5)
  - January, 1956 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Vernal Alfalfa (Box 5)
    - Blends of Alfalfa Seed NOT Recommended (Box 5)
  - February-March, 1956 (Box 5)
    - Research Project #424 (Box 5)
    - Suggestions for Plant Exploration in Europe (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - April-May, 1956 (Box 5)
    - Bulletin (Box 5)
    - Suggestions for Plant Exploration in Europe (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - June-August, 1956 (Box 5)
    - Fatis (Box 5)
    - Forage Want List for European Expedition (Box 5)
    - Forage Expedition to Europe (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - September-December, 1956 (Box 5)
    - What Every Farmer Should Know About His Seed Dealer (Box 5)
    - Statement of Increased Funds Needed (Box 5)
    - Forage Seed Inventory (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - 1957-59 (Box 5)
    - Research Line Project Annual Report of Progress (Box 5)
    - Plant Losses Due to Crown and Root Rots (Box 5)
    - Forage Projects (Box 5)
    - Alfalfa Varietal Trial (Box 5)
    - Fairway Fertilizer Trials (Box 5)
    - After Beer, What? Perhaps Turf Development (Box 5)
    - The Cause & Control of Forage Legume Diseases (Box 5)
  - 1960 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - January-February, 1961 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Fall Grain Yield Data (Box 5)
    - Grain Weights from E. Farm (Box 5)
    - Spring Grain Weights (Box 5)
    - Fertilizer Treatments and Results (Box 5)
    - Bran and Hay Weights (Box 5)
  - March-May, 1961 (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
    - Vitamins from the ocean (Box 5)
    - Pittsburgh Testing Laboratory (Box 5)
    - Reports of a Visit by a U.K. Seed Team (Box 5)
  - June-December, 1961 (Box 5)
    - Fifty Seed Varieties Improved by Schoth Before Retirement (Box 5)
    - Correspondence (Box 5)
  - February-March, 1962 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Sand Dune Control in the Pacific Northwest (Box 6)
    - U.S. Exports of Domestic Merchandise (Box 6)
  - April-June, 1962 (Box 6)
    - Date on Tall Fescue Clones (Box 6)
    - Oregon Agricultural Experiment Station, Annual Progress Report (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - July-August, 1962 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - September-October, 1962 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Registration List 21st Short Course on Roadside Development (Box 6)
  - November-December, 1962 (Box 6)
    - Subterranian Clover in the Pacific Northwest (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - January-February, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Pennlawn Red Fescue (Box 6)
    - Rainier Red Fescue (Box 6)
    - Successful Farming's Bonus (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - March-April, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Add Years to Your Life and Life to Your Years (Box 6)
    - Review of 1963 Seed Processors Short Course (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - May-July, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Highland Bentgrass (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - August-September, 1963 (Box 6)
    - Buffalo Grass (Box 6)
    - Pangola Grass (Box 6)
    - Blue Panic Grass (Box 6)
    - Paragrass (Box 6)
    - Investigation on the Control and Eradication of Gorse in Oregon (Box 6)
  - 1964 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - January-March, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Bentgrass Key (Box 6)
  - April-June, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Centennial Theme Suggestions (Box 6)
    - Proposed Revisions of Chap. 28, The Ryegrasses in "Forages" (Box 6)
    - Oregons Place in the Turf Seed Production World (Box 6)
    - Beginnings and Development of the Seed Industry in the Pacific Northwest (Box 6)
  - July-September, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Resume of Oregon's Field Seed Production (Box 6)
    - Canadian Seed Convention, July 6, 1965 (Box 6)
    - OSU Dept. of Ag. Chem. Eight Decades of Service (Box 6)
  - October-December, 1965 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - The "Icides" in Agriculture (Box 6)
    - Seed Production Plans in Europe (Box 6)
    - Soil Conservation Society of America-Oregon Chapter (Box 6)
  - January-April, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Insect Control for Commercial Holly (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - May-December, 1966 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - 1967 (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
    - Soil Test Report (Box 6)
  - February-March, 1968 (Box 6)
    - Sand Dune Stabilization Along the North Atlantic Coast (Box 6)
    - A Birdseye View of the Cape May Plant Materials Center (Box 6)
    - Bentgrass Key (Box 6)
    - Pacific Coast Reed Canary Grass Ready for Market (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, April-October, 1968; 1969 (Box 6)
    - Steak and Chop Club-minutes of Meetings (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Personal (Box 6)
    - Report on Overflow Meadows of the Colombia (Box 6)
    - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Research Papers (Box 6)
    - Seeding Pasturalands in Lincoln County (Box 6)
    - Seed Production Plans in Europe (Box 6)
    - Pasture Recommendations (Box 6)
    - Plants of the Pacific Coast (Box 6)
    - Problems of Re-Seeding Arid Range Land (Box 6)
    - Points in Connection with Production of Grass & Legume Seed Crops (Box 6)
    - Grassland Agriculture for Pacific Region (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 1930's (Box 6)
    - Rationalism in Plant Improvement (Box 6)
    - List of People who Have Inquired of Austrian Winter Peas (Box 6)
    - Distinguishing Characters of Seed of Certain Cultivated Lespedezas (Box 6)
    - Bird's Eye View of Farm News (Box 6)
    - Permission to Trespass (Box 6)
    - Irrigation Plat Yields (Box 6)
    - Analysis of Legumes of Willamette Valley (Box 6)
    - Farm Crop Seed Production in Oregon (Box 6)
    - Differentiting Characters of Grass Seeds (Box 6)
    - Harding Grass (Box 6)
    - Botanical Descriptions (Box 6)
    - Results of the Row Trials of Vetches (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous & Undated (Box 6)
    - Western Washington Conference of Vocational Agriculture Instructors (Box 6)
    - Pasture Seedlings-Western Washington (Box 6)
    - Plantings of Soil Improvements & Forage Crops in Georgia (Box 6)
    - The Use of Commercial Fertilizers for Lawns, etc. (Box 6)
    - Ryegrass Varieties and Production Methods (Box 6)
    - Removal of Honey Dew (Box 6)
    - Class Monuments (Box 6)
    - Botanical Descriptions (Box 6)
    - Charles Vancover Piper (Box 6)
    - Agricultural Projects for North Douglas County (Box 6)
    - Sales Bulletin #10 (Box 6)
    - Records of Winter Legume Growth and Nitrogen Content (Box 6)
    - Winter Legumes for Increased Crop Yields (Box 6)
    - Ladino Clover (Box 6)
    - Seed Supply Agreement for Cooprative Green Manuring (Box 6)
    - Report on Contemplated Sand Dune Control Projects (Box 6)
    - Bentgrass Seed Production in the Pacific Northwest (Box 6)
    - Newspaper Articles (Box 6)
    - Zawadke Alkali Grass (Box 6)
    - Lawns in Corvallis (Box 6)
    - Dobe Crop Trials (Box 6)
    - Turf Football Fields Possible (Box 6)
    - Legume Innoculation Experiment (Box 6)
    - Reasons for and Uses That May be Made of a Seed Council (Box 6)
    - The Pacific States Seed Industry (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, Data Etc. (Box 6)
    - Coast Botton Pastures (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 6)
- Publications, 1905-1966; Series IV
  - Grains For the Dry Lands of Central Oregon, April 1917 (Box 6)
  - Ag. Conservation Prog. 1958 Handbook (Box 6)
  - Growing the Jerusalem Artichoke, June 1936 (Box 6)
  - Decay and Other Losses in Douglas Fir in Western Oregon and Washington, April 1932 (Box 6)
  - Agriculture in the United States, 1929 (Box 6)
  - Effect of Annual Application of Diuron on Seed Yields of Perennial Grasses in Oregon, July 1966 (Box 6)
  - Grazing on the Public Lands, 1905 (Box 6)
  - Oregon Agriculture 4 The Dairy Industry, June 1946 (Box 6)
  - The Distribution and Adaptation of Poa Bulbosa in the United States and in Foreign Countries, October 1932 (Box 6)
  - Oregon's Problem in Marketing Agricultural and Industrial Products, 1938 (Box 6)
  - Farm Drainage, January 1955 (Box 6)
  - Oregon State Board of Forestry Bulletin No. 3, January 1930 (Box 6)
  - 1955 Biennial Report of Oregon Soil Conservation Committee (Box 6)
  - Farming in Oregon, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Siuslaw Soil Conservation District Annual Report, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Grazing on the Public Lands, 1905 (Box 6)
  - Proceedings of the Oregon State Horticultural Soceity and the Western Nut Growers Association, December 1939 & December 1941 (Box 6)
  - Hairy Vetch for Nebraska, February 1951 (Box 6)
  - The Phenological Types of Various Forage Crops and Their Utilities (Japanese?) (Box 6)
  - Condensed History of the U.S. Department of Agriculture, 1947 (Box 6)
  - Agriculture in Oregon, 1952 (Box 6)
  - Canadian Seed Growers' Association Inc. 1948-49 Annual Report (Box 6)
  - Report to the Nation, 1941 (Box 6)
  - Research in Oregon, undated (Box 6)
  - Oregon Agricultural College Farm Crops Department (Box 6)
- Bulletin of the Green Section of the U.S. Golf Association, 1921-1933; Series V
  - Vol. 1, 1921 (Box 7)
  - Vol. 2, 1922 and vol. 3, 1923 (Box 7)
  - Vol. 4, 1924 (Box 7)
  - Vol. 5, 1925 (Box 7)
  - Vol. 6, 1926 (Box 8)
  - Vol. 7, 1927 (Box 8)
  - Vol. 8, 1928 (Box 8)
  - Vol. 9, 1929 (Box 8)
  - Vol. 10, 1930 (Box 8)
  - Vol. 11, 1931 (Box 9)
  - Vol. 12, 1932 (Box 9)
  - Vol. 13, 1933 (Box 9)
- Field Notebooks, 1914-1960; Series VI
  - Vetch experiments (Homer M. Carnes), 1914-15 (Box 9)